iobit.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy - IObit

Last Updated: February 18, 2019

IObit is committed to protecting your privacy all the time. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of what information we collect, use and share when you visit our websites and/or use our products and services.

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by IObit through the majority of its websites and services, as well as its offline product support services. This policy does not apply to those IObit sites, services and products that do not display or link to this policy, or that have their own privacy statements.

This policy applies to the following products: Advanced SystemCare, Advanced SystemCare Ultimate, IObit Malware Fighter, Driver Booster, Smart Defrag, IObit Uninstaller, IObit Software Updater, MacBooster, Start Menu 8, Protected Folder, Random Password Generator, IObit Unlocker, WinMetro, iFreeUp, IObit Undelete, AMC Security, AMC Cleaner, and IObit Applock. 

Please read this Privacy Policy so that you know and understand what information we collect and how we use, protect, and share the information.

If you have any questions about this Policy, please feel free to contact us.

### What Information We Collect and How We Collect

When you visit our websites, use our products, or contact us by email or otherwise, we may collect or ask you to provide the following information in order to help us manage our relationship with you.

**Use of Cookies**

"Cookies" are small text files that are placed on your computer or device when you visit our Site. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently. The data we acquire from cookies may be processed by Google Analytics and may be used to determine your geographic location so that we can deliver content in your local language. By using our Site, you consent to the use of cookies as described in this privacy policy. But you have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer.

Google Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google. IObit uses Google Analytics cookies to help us understand the use of our Site by our visitors, compile reports on your website activity, and provide other services relating to website activity and internet usage. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google. Google's privacy policy is available at <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

IObit may also use "cookies" to record your shopping cart contents and user registration information. Cookies can help us identify your preferences, like language and currency. At the same time, cookies can help you personalize your online experience by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information and to display your personalized content and appropriate advertising on your later visits to these sites.

**Use of Third Party Ad Networks and Social Networks**

The majority of the online banner advertisements you see on IObit web pages are displayed by IObit. However, we allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to display advertisements on IObit web pages. We may use [third-party advertising companies](http://d2hdvagpl7duen.cloudfront.net/pp.html) to serve ads when you visit our website. Some of these ad networks may place a persistent cookie on your computer or device in order to recognize your computer or device each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad networks may compile information about where you are, or who are using your computer or device, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. IObit does not have access to the cookies that may be placed by the third-party ad servers or ad networks.

If you choose to ‘share’ IObit products with friends through Facebook, Twitter or other social networks, you might be sent cookies from these websites. We don’t control the setting of these cookies, so please check those websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.

**Placing Orders**

When you purchase "premium" (or paid) products or services from IObit, the billing is handled by a third-party service provider, who is acting on our behalf; thus, you will make your purchase from the service provider directly, and not from IObit. The handling of your personal information will be governed by any privacy policy or terms of service published by the service provider. 

The service provider may request billing information such as your name, email address, home or work address, telephone or mobile phone number, payment information including credit card number, expiration date, security code, name of your issuing bank, etc. The purpose of this information is to fulfill orders, process payment, deliver products, provide customer service, and the like. The third-party service provider may transmit some of your personal information to us, but not including payment information. We may use the information we receive to verify your registration, to contact you about the status of your order, for renewal of your subscription, or for other offers you may be interested, if applicable.

We have agreements with all the third-party service providers that they will not use personal information of our users for their own marketing purposes, and will not share this information with other parties.

**News Subscriptions**

Our website offers news and information by subscription including newsletters, blogs, or others. If you decide to subscribe to these services you are asked to provide email address. The information you provide will be used to deliver our latest news and updates, and of course, our special subscriber-only offers. You are free to edit your profile and cancel your subscription(s) at any time by following the "edit profile" or "unsubscribe" link inside any e-mail you receive from us.

**IObit Forum**

If you decide to register IObit Forum, you will be asked to select a username, password, email address, physical location, native language, your computer or device details, and IObit software you installed.

**Customer Testimonials**

We display name, testimonials and pictures of satisfied customers on our websites with their consent. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, please contact us with your request. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

**Contact Us and Technical Support Service**

We may collect or ask you to provide necessary information when you reach us by email, by signing up our Affiliate Program, or by requesting online support.

This information may include, without limitation, your name, your email address, your website, your physical address and ZIP code, what features you use in our software, how you use our software, your computer or device information such as hardware and system version, system services, processes, startup items, registry entries, dump files, crash logs, etc. In general, we collect no more information than is required in order to investigate the issue you encounter.

This information is collected to help us to provide services and support, to identify and remove computer or device viruses, and to help us solve the technology problems you are experiencing. By sending the related information to us, you agree to share them with IObit. If you do not want to share the information with IObit, you can just uncheck the related option or close the related window. We will use any such information only when providing individual support or assistance, and will not retain such information any longer than necessary for this purpose. We promise that we will never publish or share any of your personally identifiable information outside IObit, nor allow anyone else to use it to contact you for marketing purposes without your consent.

**Mobile Application User Experience Improvement Plan (UX Improvement Plan)**

The UX Improvement Plan may collect information, including, but not limited to, system version, country, language, and app version. The collected information is used to help us improve our products and to enhance your user experience. 

Participation in UX Improvement Plan is completely voluntary. You can opt in or opt out at any time by switching on or off the toggle in Settings of IObit mobile application. By joining the User Experience Improvement Plan, you agree to share the information with IObit. We promise that we will never publish or share any of your personally identifiable information outside IObit, nor allow anyone else to use it to contact you for marketing purposes without your consent.

**Non-Personal Information**

We may collect some non-personal information which aims to validate your registration and to know how you use our software or services. The information may include operating system, device ID, Internet protocol addresses, browser type, browser language, referring/exit pages, clickstream data of our websites and our products or services, and the pages or features of our software or services accessed by you and the time spent there.

### How We Use the Information We Collect

IObit collects and uses your personal information to operate and improve its sites and products and deliver the services or carry out the transactions you have requested. These uses may include providing you with more effective customer service; making the sites or services easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information; performing research and analysis aimed at improving our products, services and technologies; and displaying content and advertising that are customized to your interests and preferences.

We also use your personal information to communicate with you. We may send certain mandatory service communications such as welcome letters, billing reminders, information on technical service issues, and security announcements. Some IObit services, such as IObit Newsletter, may send periodic member letters that are considered part of the service. We may also occasionally send you product surveys or promotional mailings to inform you of other products or services available from IObit and its affiliates.

Personal information collected on IObit sites and services may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which IObit or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using an IObit site or service, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. IObit abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

### How We Protect the Information We Collect

**Safeguards for Personal Information.**

IObit is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We have implemented a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. These measures include:

  * **Storage of Your Information**  
We store the personal information you provide on computer or device systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities.
  * **Technology safeguards**  
When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layers (SSL) protocol.

No one can guarantee, and we do not guarantee, that your personal information is completely secure at all times. You are also responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your personal information to protect it against unauthorized access or use. If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer or device with anyone you should always choose to log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users.

**Controlling "Spam" or Unsolicited E-mail**

IObit is concerned about controlling unsolicited commercial email, or "spam". IObit has a strict Anti-Spam Policy prohibiting the use of customer account to send spam. IObit will not sell, lease or rent its email subscriber lists to third parties. While IObit continues to actively review and implement new technology, such as expanded filtering features, there is no currently available technology that will totally prevent the sending and receiving of unsolicited email. Using tools such as the Inbox Protector and being cautious about the sharing of your email address while online will help reduce the amount of unsolicited email you receive.

**Children's Policy**

IObit products and services are not intended for and may not be used by children under sixteen. We do not knowingly collect information from children under sixteen. We encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. If we learn that we have collected information of a child under sixteen, we will delete such information from our files as soon as possible, but some information may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law.

### How We Share Your Information

IObit does not share or disclose your personal information to any third parties with two exceptions as below:

**Third-Party Service Providers**

We may hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, hosting websites, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. Those companies will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose.

**Government and Law Enforcement**

We may access and/or disclose your personal information if we believe such action is necessary to: (a) comply with the law or legal process served on IObit; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of IObit (including the enforcement of our agreements); or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of IObit services or members of the public.

### How to Change or Delete Your Personal Information

If you want us to correct, amend, or delete your personal information, your forum account, newsletter subscriptions, or your support tickets, please contact us with your request. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. However, some information may remain in archived/backup copies to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

For the information processed by the third party partners, you have the right to access your personal information. If you want to access, correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data on our third party partner's platform, you should contact them directly as they are the data controllers and IObit has no control of those information.

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the "Last Updated" date at the top of this statement. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be informed of how IObit is protecting your information.

### Contact Information

IObit regularly reviews its compliance with this Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy or IObit's treatment of personal information by contacting us through this website. If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or believe that IObit has not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please contact us and we will make efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
